Preliminary Guide to the Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project records, 2000-2002 RL.00325
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project records
2000-2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies. Community Programs
RL.00325
1.8 Linear Feet
The Durham Traditional Arts Survey was conducted in the early 2000s as part of the Document Durham project within the Community Programs department at the Center for Documentary Studies. Participants consisted of folklorists and photographers who traveled through Durham County, attempting to document the diversity of various communities by focusing on traditional artists within those communities. One outcome of the DTAS was the Home Made Visible: Durham 2002 exhibition, which highlighted Durham traditional arts and crafts. Includes fieldwork reports, interview tapes, slides, photographs, and other documentary material from the research and observations conducted by participants in the Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project. Durham communities and artists represented in the project include African American, African immigrants, Latino, Middle Eastern, Jewish, South Indian, and Asian, as well as occupational traditions and rural community traditions. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts.
900 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Historical Note
The Durham Traditional Arts Survey was conducted in the early 2000s as part of the Document Durham project within the Community Programs department at the Center for Documentary Studies. Participants consisted of folklorists and photographers who traveled through Durham County, attempting to document the diversity of various communities by focusing on traditional artists within those communities. One outcome of the DTAS was the Home Made Visible: Durham 2002 exhibition, which highlighted Durham traditional arts and crafts.
Collection Overview
Includes fieldwork reports, interview tapes, slides, photographs, and other documentary material from the research and observations conducted by participants in the Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project. Durham communities and artists represented in the project include African American, African immigrants, Latino, Middle Eastern, Jewish, South Indian, and Asian, as well as occupational traditions and rural community traditions. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts.
Color slides; Documentary films; Negatives (photographic); Durham (N.C.) -- Social life and customs; Young photographers -- North Carolina -- Durham; Durham (N.C.) -- Arts and crafts; Audiocassettes; Floppy disks; Digital audio tapes; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Lau, Barbara (Barbara A.); Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies. Community Programs
- Accession (2009-0085), dated 2000-2002, 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes fieldwork reports, interview tapes, slides, photographs, and other documentary material from the research and observations conducted by participants in the Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project. Durham communities and artists represented in the project include African American, African immigrants, Latino, Middle Eastern, Jewish, South Indian, and Asian, as well as occupational traditions and rural community traditions. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts.
  Arrangement note
  This accession has not been processed, and the arrangement reflects the condition of the collection as it arrived at Duke Special Collections. Materials appear to have been sorted by the name of each fieldworker participating in the project. Boxes 1 and 2 include the project's administrative files, final reports, interview notes, and in many cases the audiocassettes or electronic media used by the fieldworker. Box 3 contains photographs, negatives, slides, and contact sheets, also arranged by participant.
  - Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project administrative files (Box 1)
  - Durham Traditional Arts Survey Project overview documents, Home Made Visible exhibit (product), 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Home Made Visible exhibit booklet (Box 1)
  - Mary Lee fieldnotes, photographic log, 2001 December 1 (includes 1 floppy disk) (Box 1)
  - Sneha Shah, 2001 December 1. Interviewer: Mary Lee (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 1)
  - Kruti Desai and Mehul Desai, 2001 December 2. Interviewer: Mary Lee (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 1)
  - Sarvamangala Tadepalli, 2001 December 6. Interviewer: Mary Lee (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 1)
  - Linda Davis, 2001 December 1. Interviewer: Mary Lee (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 1)
  - Sapna Karth, 2001 December 1. Interviewer: Mary Lee (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 1)
  - Mary-Anne McDonald and Ann-Marie Villanova. Latino culture, 2001 January-May (includes 1 floppy disk and 2 minidiscs) (Box 1)
  - Braima Moiwai, 2001 November 28. Interviewer: Michelle Lanier Segbefia (includes 2 audiocassettes) (Box 1)
  - Zakiah Moukanna. Interviewer: Barbara Lau (includes 2 audiocassettes) (Box 2)
  - Maria Horvath/John Horvath, 2001 November 12. Interviewer: Barbara Lau (Box 2)
  - Clellie White, 2001 February 27. Interviewer: Lesley Williams (Box 2)
  - William Lewis, researcher fieldnotes (Box 2)
  - Pearl Holman, 2001 October 19. Interviewer: William Lewis (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 2)
  - Matt Yarborough, 2001 October 17. Interviewer: William Lewis (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 2)
  - George Peaks Jr., 2001 October 22. Interviewer: William Lewis (includes 1 audiocassette) (Box 2)
  - Tosh Tanaka, Asian community researcher (Box 2)
  - Debbie Suchoff, 2001 October 14. Interviewer: Nancy Kalow (includes digital audiotape) (Box 2)
  - Steve Herman, 2001 October 10. Interviewer: Nancy Kalow (Box 2)
  - Galia Goodman, 2001 October 18. Interviewer: Nancy Kalow (includes 2 digital audiotapes) (Box 2)
  - Nancy Kalow fieldnotes and photo logs (Box 2)
  - Mark Sheftall fieldnotes (Box 2)
  - Negatives, prints, and contact sheets (Box 3)
    - Tom Rankin
      - John Horvath, negatives and slides (Box 3)
      - Zakiah Moukanna (embroidery), slides (Box 3)
      - Clellie White (hatmaker), slides (Box 3)
      - Little River (quilter), prints (Box 3)
      - Zakiah Moukanna, prints (Box 3)
      - Ken Maynor, prints (Box 3)
      - Clellie White, prints (Box 3)
    - Michelle McCullers Segbefia
      - Braima Moiwai gara (Box 3)
    - Mark David Sheftall
      - Joseph Parker, negatives and prints (Box 3)
    - Rosey Truong (now Hong-An Truong)
      - Galia Goodman (Box 3)
      - Steve Henry Herman (Box 3)
      - Braima Moiwai (Box 3)
    - Louis Velasco
      - Photos of Home Made Visible exhibit at Durham Arts Center, February 2002 (Box 3)
      - Preparation and celebration of the Feast of Virgen de Guadelupe, December 2001 (Box 3)
    - Lesley Williams
      - Clellie White and homemade hats (Box 3)
    - Barbara Lau
      - Durham Christmas Parade, December 2000 (Box 3)
    - Nancy Kalow
      - Durham's Indian community (Box 3)
    - William Lewis (Box 3)
    - Mary Ann McDonald and Anne Marie Villasana
      - Immaculate Conception Church, Chapel Hill (Box 3)